mishraalokji@gmail.com +919595704944

Noida, India 201014

WWW: Bold Profile

Skills

- Business Development
- Strategic Planning
- Financial Management
- Operations Management
- Staff Development
- Policy Implementation
- Performance Management
- Project Management
- Staff Training and Development
- Negotiation
- Budget Control

Education And Training

02/2010

MBA:

Supply Chain Management
Suryadatta Group Of Institute
Pune

Languages

Hindi: First Language

English: C1
Advanced (C1)
Marathi: A1

Beginner

Alok Mishra

Summary

Forward-thinking Manager with comprehensive experience implementing new processes and managing and planning innovations. Bringing outstanding problem-solving and abilities paired with in-depth knowledge of policies and procedures. Polished in evaluating employee performance and overseeing key projects.

Experience

Tata 1mg - Manager Supply Chain Excellence

Noida, India

11/2021 - Current

Current Profile:

- Established processes to ensure efficient workflow throughout the organization.
- Monitored budgets and expenditures to ensure cost-effectiveness while maintaining quality standards.
- Initiated new projects that resulted in increased productivity across all departments.
- Implemented new technologies to streamline operations, reduce costs, and improve customer service.
- Deploying new projects in warehouses across India.

Previous Profile:

- Handling the entire operation (Inbound, Inventory, Outbound, B2B) of the FC.
- Manage for cost and productivity in warehouse operation.
- Hire, motivate, train and sustain a high performance warehouse team.
- Manage the performance and cost of drivers attached to the warehouse.
- Setup layout and ensure efficient space utilization.
- Taking care of all complaisance.
- Almost handling 400+ Manpower (Off Roll + On roll)
- Ensure KPI targets are developed, communicated and monitored on a daily basis.
- Develop the weekly Key Performance reporting, with analysis to ensure an efficient and cost effective Warehouse Operations
- Implement effective processes to ensure NO Inventory loss to the Company.
- Ensure adequate levels of appropriately trained employees are available to effectively maintain
- · Customer Service Levels.
- Ensure all Employees/Contractors are inducted and receive regular training required to perform their job Safely.
- Customer Focus identifies and responds to Customers needs and ensures quality of service standards are met at all times.

Flipkart Internet Pvt Ltd - Team Leader

Mumbai

07/2018 - 11/2021

- Handling Alpha lite operation At West Zone.
- 30 Alpha Lite sites Entire West Zone whole operation (Inbound ,Inventory ,Outbound) handling.
- Co-ordination with brand SPOC as well as central team and IT Team for smooth operation.
- Maintaining inventory sanity with no variance.
- Preparing Penalty calculation to the brands if they breached any metrics.
- Providing Training to staff regarding the process and system.
- Handling The warehouse operation (5 Lakh Squire Ft.)
- Works In various department like inbound, Inventory Management, and Outbound.
- Ensure efficiency in warehouse functions & reducing operation Cost.

Renfro India Pvt. Ltd. - Assistant Warehouse Manager

Pune, India

02/2011 - 07/2018

- Ensured accuracy of shipping and receiving documents.
- Monitored inventory levels to ensure efficient stock control.
- Developed and implemented safety policies and procedures for warehouse staff.
- Coordinated with other departments to ensure timely order fulfillment.
- Provided training on proper use of equipment and safety protocols.
- Maintained records of goods received, stored, shipped, or in process.
- Managed daily operations including scheduling personnel and assigning tasks.
- Resolved customer complaints regarding deliveries, quality issues.
- Inspected warehouse areas to identify potential hazards and unsafe conditions.
- Established processes to improve efficiency of warehouse operations.
- Analyzed data related to supply chain management activities such as delivery times, cost savings.

Origin Logistics Pvt Ltd - Warehouse Executive

Pune, India

02/2010 - 02/2011

Activities And Honors

 Work In multiple departments like Warehouse Operation ,Logistics,Supply Chain Excellence

Accomplishments

Tata 1mg

- In Tata 1mg I have got the responsibility to handle the largest B2C operation warehouse of pan India ,after setting it up the warehouse of B2B operation was also given to me.
- Here I got the opportunity to handle the largest team size 440 manpower
- After one year I have got the opportunity from central to join Supply Chain Excellence Team.
- \bullet Also I completed project Paper & Printing cost reduction where i save 50% cost (0.70 INR Per Order)

Flipkart

- In Flipkart I have got a chance in training department as Kool Guru and have got second Rank in West Zone .
- Opportunity to handle 200 employee people team .
- Also before my joining new off roll employee learning period was 21 days and I reduce this time 21 to 11 days .
- Opportunity to handle new project Alphalite ,here I handled 35 warehouse
- Opportunity to handle the operation of entire west Zone Renfro India Pvt Ltd
- Joined As a Junior Trainee –SCM (2011) in the organization (Renfro India Pvt. Ltd) Last Position was Asst.Manager –Operation of Distribution Centre and handling 45 Person Team in same organization.
- Working under two system environment which are listed below A-ERP

B-SAP-WM MODULE

Personal Details

• Name: Alok Mishra

• Father's Name: Shriprakash Mishra

• DOB: 25/08/1987

• Sex : Male

Marital Status: Married

· Languages Known: English, Hindi

• Nationality: Indian

• Permanent Address : New Sainik Coloney Nagaladeena Fatehgarh - State UP Pin-209601

• Current Address : House Number - 554 Second Floor Near Swarna Jayanti Park UP-201014

• Religious : Hindu

• Contact Number: 9595704944/8421783235

• Email: mishraalokji@gmail.com

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information given above is true and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief

Date:

Name: Alok Mishra